back uh still tuned in to the market
you've got uh the index staring at about
17,23 while names like hindalco hdsc
life SBI and M&M are seeing pressure in
trade adani ports is up about 3% HCL
Tech as well as bti AEL and maruti
Suzuki at about
7904 but let's connect with the
management of IC Lombard bhav Das Gupta
MD and CEO of the company now joining in
to talk about their quarterly earnings
the outlook for the insurance sector as
well as demand Trends thank you so much
for taking time out let's begin with the
numbers because your Q4 profits were
down nearly 4% and that's been coupled
with an increase in the combined ratio
walk us through the quarter as well as
the year gone by and what have been some
of the key highlights for the
company so you know this was for us a
good quarter in terms of growth uh if
you see our first 9mon number U you know
the growth was a bit muted I'm not
looking at a stand loone of last year
because if you look at our Standalone
number for us last year the growth for
the industry for a company has been
about 20 28% but I'm looking at the
number aggregating bti AA book because
that's the way to look at it right
because this year number has a bti AA
business Incorporated so if you look at
the company as a whole and if I add IC
Lombard number last year to and to it we
add the bti a number our growth for the
company for the year has been a Shar
lower than 5% but if you look at just
this quarter gone by that growth number
is significantly higher and within that
if you look at the March numbers it's
much higher and in fact we've outgrown
the market even with you know the base
of bti added to the to the base numbers
so in terms of growth it has been a good
quarter in terms of combined there are
two uh two or three factors one when you
look at Vis our last year numbers when
you integrated the two companies bti
access combined was always high and we
had said that it'll take us a Glide part
path of a couple of years to bring it
under control so when you look at bti
ACC number they were you know before the
merger announcement they were around 120
so on an integrated basis that would
have been anywhere around 104 if you
look at our number last quarter which
was with the BH EXA book added that was
104 it's come down to 103 now coming to
your profit uh you know Point uh there
are largely two reasons one we had the
wave three covid losses which is uh uh
which was roughly about 27 CR uh you
know uh you know for the quarter and
about 550 crores for the year uh if you
look at uh apart from that there was
another reason you know if you look at
the accounting for insurance the
accounting for insurance policies is
such that you have to take the entire
cost of sourcing that business upfront
and you take the revenue which is the
earned premium over the period of the
policy so for us if it's a 12-month
policy largely U and you write a lot of
business in the month of March you take
the full cost of that sourcing in in the
month of March but the income the Top
Line comes over the next uh you know 12
months
now given that Health has definitely
been the focus ICI Lombard has also
managed to outpace the industry average
help us understand how Trends are now
shaping up and what is the that the
compan is doing differently to stand
out I think that's a great question so
if you see you know uh we believe a
long-term shift in the way Health
consumption behavior is going to change
and this is not just because of the
pandemic and the digitization we are
seeing but this has been a global trend
for some time we believe that Health
consumption will be very very personal
uh very self-driven and very digitized
in the long term uh traditionally health
insurance in India has focused on just
the hospitalization cost right so you uh
you get you know you get some severe
illness you need a hospitalization you
uh you know insurance pays for it but
healthare is beyond that I mean
healthare is about a Continuum of Care
uh preventive Wellness your Fitness
hygiene as also Outpatient Care
uh you know normal doctor visits and uh
hospitalization if you required so
that's the approach that we are taking
if you look at our approach on our I
take care app uh we are providing the
entire continum of care including a pure
insurance policy for OPD uh you know
costs as also the wellness the
preventive the uh you know advisory the
fitness and all of that that we talking
about so all of that is something that
we are building uh and the other thing
that we've seen is that you know people
are willing to consume health on on a
digital mode so a lot of tele Health lot
of video based Consulting increasingly
homebased care if the ailment is not
very very severe so all of these are
components that we building and you know
over the last two years we believe lot
of it has been built out and we are now
investing in terms of scaling up
distribution so if you see our this
quarter growth uh about 6 months back we
started hiring a lot of agency managers
who come on board uh you know hired
their own agents and the business is now
scaling up
shifting Focus Mr Das Gupta to your crop
insurance business as well because that
seems to have picked up over the last
few years and seems to be contributing
well to your business as well tell us a
bit more about this space how are you
managing the risk what is unique and how
do you see it performing in the coming
years so for us uh till we did the
integration with bti we were we did not
have any crop insurance business we used
to ride crop earlier but we you know we
went out of the business uh with bti
acquisition we've inherited some of the
crop business that they were writing uh
so when you see our numbers this year
that has the bti book that has come in
now if you see the crop insurance
business now most of the commitments are
for a longer term period so we will have
we will stay invested in that in that
business for that period in terms of
what we are seeing for the bti booker
has been profitable even for us you know
in the in the integrated business for uh
at least for the year gone by we believe
it will be profitable we are watching
the entire crop cutting experimentation
before we take a final call on the
profitability we are holding reserves
conservatively at this point in time in
terms of looking at the future uh you
know what is happening is that you know
gradually the scheme seems to be
changing a bit some states have gone
away some states are going into a model
which is not you know completely
transferring of risk but it's a range BR
model where if the loss isue is below
80% then the insurer will have to refund
the premium if it is more than 110 the
you know the state will step in and pay
the claims so it's a range bound product
that is kind of uh uh evolving in you
know a few states have opted for that
few states have opted out of the
insurance scheme so there's a lot of
change happening and our sense is that
there is a need for using uh you know
data which is uh you know independent of
human driven crop cutting process to
identify and and pay claims that will
make it faster and and you know more
convenient for uh for the farmers uh you
know use satellite data Maybe build
capability of drone based imagery Etc
and that's something that we believe is
needed to be built and I think ideally
there should be an institution which
does this independent of the state and
the insurance company so that there's
more credibility in terms of the actual
losses that we pay
for sure point taken but talk to us
about your other segments the motor
insurance fire Insurance segments how
are you seeing the demand momentum in
these and any specific sector which you
are seeing is getting a lot of
traction look for the year gone by motor
was very T so if you see one of the
biggest shifts that has happened this
year is because Health has grown well
motor hasn't uh in the overall basket of
uh the segments Health has become number
one for the general insurance industry
traditionally motor has been the biggest
segment so this year for the first time
Health constitutes about 33% of the
market uh motor is roughly about 30 31%
of the market so this is in a sense a
quite a you know big shift for the
industry but this is as I said was
largely driven by the fact that new
vehicle sales were muted for two
wheelers we had two consecutive years
years of muted sales largely driven by
demand issues on the private car side
you know in the beginning we had some uh
good growth driven by the base effect
the previous year but if you see the
last quarter the growth has been very
very tied in fact negative uh again this
time it's been driven by the supply side
issues in terms of Chip short so this
has been the past commercial has is
beginning to pick up but for the next
year we are a bit more optimistic about
motor we believe that given this base of
underperformance for 2 years for two
wheelers and one year for private C we
should see some growth momentum you know
come back we are hopeful that the supply
issue will also the chip shortage issue
will also get ironed out in the next
five to six months and Rural demand will
pick up for for two wheelers so we are
optimistic about the motor segment you
know looking ahead Health has had a good
run in terms of Top Line with that That
Base also we believe health will
continue to grow because it's a very
underp sector and there is a clear
understanding of the need for edicate
health insurance in the mind of the
consumer because of what all of us have
gone through for the last two years so
that's also a positive think the
commercial lines which is for the
corporates we are seeing uh lot more
investment in infrastructure you know
now we are also seeing some amount of
capacity addition that is happening
across certain sectors largely for by
internal ACS you know and and and and
maybe some International BS but we
seeing some of that so we see positive
momentum even in the commercial lines so
we believe the industry should grow well
next year maybe in the mid teens or low
teens uh you know on the back of maybe
about an 11% growth that we've seen this
walk us through how pricing Trends are
shaping up because I understand you
expect that premiums will uh you know
continue to see growth in the current
environment are you seeing higher risks
uh especially in wealth and uh you know
cost of vehicles as well having gone
up yeah so inflation has an impact for
all of us and you've rightly identified
the uh aspects of inflation as it
affects our industry so motor uh we have
taken some small price increase uh
largely driven by the fact that motor
pricing was very very aggressive because
as an industry uh you know for the last
two years people have just gone for
market share maybe hoping for some
frequency drops in in terms of claims
but that is behind us uh you know we are
seeing High you know reasonably back to
normal frequency in terms of claims and
we are seeing some amount of inflation
so we've taken some uh single digit
price increases in the motor OD own
damage segment for the private car on
the TP side uh the claim inflation that
we see and these are driven by court
orders and wage inflation uh that
inflation has been a double- digit
number for the industry for a long long
period of time but for almost 3 years
we've not had a price increase so we are
hope because it's a regulated product
and in last couple of years we've not
had a price increase we are hopeful that
this year we'll get to see the price
increase there is an exposure draft it's
a small increase of roughly about 3% on
a portfolio basis uh but uh so be it
even a small increase uh you know helps
on the health side um at least we are
not thinking of a price increase for our
retail customers largely because in
spite of the fact that as an industry we
paid 25,000 crores of claims on the
covid side and you know by the way and I
want to make this point to your viewers
here for the industry the total profits
is roughly about 4 to 5,000 crores and
industry's paid about 25,000 crores
claims and we've not gone out for you
know seeking any support or help from
anyone we've kind of taken in in in a
stride uh but in spite of that we are
not seeking that kind of a price
increase we as a company we are not even
planning an immediate price increase on
the retail Health
portfolio because these are we believe
one of episodes they will they will not
sustain what we do however worry about
is the healthcare infection and there we
believe there is Need for more
discipline in terms of pricing and just
because there is an affordability to pay
because of insurance Healthcare
Providers should not inflate uh you know
the cost of healthare if that happens
then in future we may
have all right we'll let you go on that
note appreciate your time Mr Das Gupta
thanks for joining in and walking us
through the demand Trends as well as
your overall quarterly performance